Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 1137. Pius V. Saint, [Michaele Gisleri), 1504-1572 (Flat-box 9, Folder 9)
    S.Pius V. Pontifex Maximimus Ord. F.F. Praedicatorum inter sanctos relatus d:Le Mali l7l2./Panisiis. Cars sculpslt anno 1713. "i~me ad vivum ano 1567 aetat 64, Pontif. Bust looking left in lettered oval, i~ froflt of stone wall. Papal coat of arms in center of baroque plinth. Engraving. 25.5 x 19.4 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1138. Pius VII, [Gregorio Barnaba Chiaromonti], 1742-1823 (Flat-box 9, Folder 9)
    Pope Pius the 7th./Sir Tho. Lawrence P.R.A. Edwd Mc Innic./London Published Sep~ 1. 1840. by Hadgson & Graves Printsellers by Special Appointment to Hen Majesty G.Pall Mall/ Seated portrait in oblong. Mezzotint. 90.5 x 27.3 cm.
  - 1139. Plato, ca 427-347 B.C. (Flat-box 9, Folder 9)
    Plato Aristonis F.Atheniensis. /Ex marmone anticuo. /P .P .Rubens delin~ /L. Vorsterman sculp./Cum privilegiis Regis Chnistianissiir.i./Principum Belgarum et 3rd. Bataviae. Sculptured bust looking left. Engraving. 29.6 x 18.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 24012/72980.
  - 1140. Plato, ca 427 B.C.-347 B.C. (Flat-box 9, Folder 9)
    Divinus Plato./H.Padoanus inventor./F.L.D. Ciartres excud. Cum Privilegio. Bust in oblong looking slightly right. Etching. 27.2 x 18.9 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. No. 22 from unidentified series
  - 1141. Playford, John, 1623-1686 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Johannis Playford Effigies./Aet.Suae 47. F.H,van Houe sculp. Bust in oval looking right in oblong. Engraving. 14.8 x 9.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1142. Plymouth, Charles, earl of, 17th cent. (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Don. Carlo. Earl of Plymouth./I.Smith exc. Knee-piece in oval looking right. Mezzotint. 33.9 x 25.2 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1143. Poelenburgh, Cornelis van, 1586-1667 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Cornelis Poulenbourgh./Natif de Utrecht peinetre trés perfaict, et admirable, en pe- tites figures, et animaux; at les enfans/nuds, il les faict fort naturelles. Ses ruines paysages, at elongements son fort beaux, il a/ demeuré longtemps en Italie; et en l’an 1637 ii fut demandd par le Roy d’Angleterne/a Londres, ou il a faict pour le Roy quelque tableaux, at la il est retire a Utnecht./Cor.Poulenbourgh delin. Coen Woumans sculp. lo. Meyssens exc. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 16.2 x 11.4 cm. Singer No. 24077/73153. From: Meyssens J., The true Effigies of the most eminent Painters that have flourished in Europe..~Engraven, [Anvers], 1694.
  - 1144. Poelenburgh, Cornelis van, 1586-1667 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Cornelius Poelenburgh,/Hollandus Pictor In Minoribus/Figuris Humanis./Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Petrus de lode sculpsit. Gum pnivilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 23.3 x 16.4 cm. Singer No. 24077/73146. Dutuit No. 42.6e. Mauquoy-H. No. 35.VIII. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1145. Poemer, Bartholomaeus, 1533-1590 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Bartholomeus Poemerus Reip. Norimb.Senator Tniumvir E~clesiarun Curator et Scalarcha Primanius./Nat.9.Nartii 1533. oh. 25 Octob. 1590./Joh.ALex BGnei se A.l666. Bust in lettered oval looking left. "Norica mirarms, anturr Respublica noTen/ Quare prae reliquis macta sit Urbibus:/Prudemtam una fa:it Moderat o nempe Senatum/qua Virtute suis imperat optimè./Hacq super reliquos excellirt Optimus oinnes Poemerus, patril gloria stemmatis,/Quem dolet, ob multos Academia nostra lebores/Quod mors lntrepide Solva peremerit./Nic. Turellus, D.et Prof. Pub.Altdorf”, under portrait Engraving. 19.7 x 13.2 cm.
  - 1146. Poemer, Georg Abraham, ca 1654 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Georgius Abraham Poemen Reip. Nonimberg Duumvir.Cas:riq Imp. Prmefectus Aetat LXX. Anno MDCLIII. Insignis Pictas, quam pictam Cernimus onis /Poemeri tandem sac rediviva cluet./Johann Pfann sculps. Hieron Ammon f. Bust in lettered oval looking night. Engraving. 17.0 x 11.7 cm. Singer No. 24089/73176.
  - 1147. Pole, Reginald, abp. of Canterbury, 1500-1558 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Portrait du Cardinal Polus/D' aprOs le Tableau de Rap1~ adi o'~ dc Era ehastien del Piombo, qua est dams le Cabinet de N.Crozat./haut de 3.pieds 5 prouces, large de 2 pieds 10,5 pouces, peint sun toile grave par Nicolas de Larmessin. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking right. Engraving. 33.3 x 25.1 cm. Singer No. 24150/73295. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1148. Pole, Reginald, abp. of Canterbury, 1500-1558 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Polus./Jestois du Sang royal mais mauvaise politique/j'invocGe ci XX Rol qui mit ma tate a prix./Le Papa cependant n'eut pour moi qua raepris/Et par tout ma vertu a cut qu'una fin tragique./Adr.van den Werff pinxit. Bust in circle looking slightly left. Engraving. 31.7 x 18.2 cm. Singer No. 24150/73292.
  - 1149. Pole, Reginald, abp. of Canterbury, 1500-1558 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Reginald Pole/Cardinal/ Natus 1600./Engraved by R,Duikarton~ froir a Crayon drawing/ after the Original Picture by S.del Pimbo/London, Piiblmrhcd by S.Woodburr 1815. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 29.0 x 20.6 cm.
  - 1150. Polignac, Melchion de, 1661-1742 (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
    Melchior S.R.E. Presbyter, tituli Stae Mariae de Angelis/ad termas Candinalis de Polignac/Archiepiscopus Auscitanus Abbas at Comes Corbeiae &c./A.Panus chez la Va Daulle./ Paint par Hyacinte Rigaud, Chevalier de 1’Ordre da St.Michel./Gravé par J.Daullé, Graveur du Roy. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 30.7 x 19.3 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 24159/73331.
  - 1151. Poll, Jan van de, 18th cent. (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Jan van da Poll/Burgemeester en Raad den Stad Amsterdam./J.Houbraken fecit na't Schildery als Kolomel van de Burgery by Merv.de Weeda, van den Hear Burgemr.Kn.Hk.van de Poll. Engraving. 18.1 x 12.1 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1152. Polyandar [a Karckhoven], Jan, 1568-1646 (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Johannes Polyander SS.Thaologiae Doctor ac Professor Leydensis Anno Domini 1519. Aetat. 51. Pie at Prudenter./M,a Mierevaldt pinxit. W.Delfft sculpsit/et axe. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Six lines of eulogy under portrait. Engraving. 18.3 x 12.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off
  - 1153. Pompeia, wife of Caesar, lst emperor of Rome, 1st cent. B.C. (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Pompeia Julii Caes.Uxor./[Double quatrain under picture]. Aegidius Sadeler S.C.M. sculp. Marcus Sadeler excudit, No.1. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 24.7 x 24.1 cm.
  - 1154. Pont, Pontius Paul du, 1603-1658 (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Paulus du Pont.Graveur admirable en Tailla douce, natif d’Anvers l’an 1603, 11 a faict/son aprentisage chez Lucas Vostermans, at at demeurè auprés Monsr./Rubens,ou ii a faict quantité de Chefs d’oeuvres; ausi pour Monsr. van/Dyck, comma on volt per ses oeuvres./I.Livens pinxit. P.de lode sculpsit. J.Meyssens axe. Bust in oblong looking left. Engraving. 16.2 x 11.2 cm. Singer No. 24215/73461. From: Meyssens J., The true Effigies of the most eminent Painters that have flourished in Europe.. .Engnaven, [Anvers], 1694
  - 1155. Pont, Pontius Paulus du, 16O3-1658 (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Paulus Pontius/Calcographus Antverpiaa./Ant.van Dyck pimxit. Paul Pontius sculp. Gum pnivilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 24.7 x 18.2 cm. Singer No. 24215/73458. Dutuit No. 65.5e. Mauquoy-H. No, 59.VI. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1156. Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744 (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Mr. Pope/J.Richardson fecit. 1738. Unframed right profile in oblong, line in Greek. Etching. 14.5 x 11.4 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1157. Pope, Sir Thomas, 1507-1559 (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Thomas Pope Miles Coll. Trinitatis Fund.r A.D. 1555./Hanc Effigiem Rev, do Viro Gull. Dobsom S.T.P. at istius. Coll:Pnaesidi Dignissimo. a/Tabul2 in suis Aedibus Asserv.ta factam. Summa cum Humil: & observantia D.D.D. J. Faber. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 26.2 x 20.2 cm. Singer No. 24238/73528.
  - 1158. Pope, Sir Thomas, 1507-1559
  - 1159. Porter, Endymion, 17th cent. (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Endymion Porter. /Attendad Prince Charles into Spain./From a beautiful Miniature in the/Possession of Lady Sutton./London Published by S.Woodburn l8lO/S.Cooper pinxit. R.Earlom sc.t. Bust in oval looking left. Mezzotint. 15.7 x 10.3 cm.
  - 1160. Portland, Richard Weston, 1st earl of, 1577-1635 (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
    Jerom Weston Earl of Portland. /& Heyland ./Van Dyck pinx. Bust looking right. Engraving. 17.8 x 10.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1161. Portland, Richard Weston, 1st earl of, 1577-1635 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    Richard Weston. Earl of Portland./From an original :: Vandyke in the Collection of/ The Right Hon,ble The Earl of Verulam./Drawn by R.W.Sa:rm’well & Engraved (with Permission by R.Cooper./London Published Sept.r. 1.1817 by Lackin~::m, Hughes, Harding, Mayor & Jonas and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm.
  - 1162. Potter, Paulus, 1625-1654 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    Paul Potter./Aubert sculp. Bust in bexoque oval looking left. Engraving. 11.7 x 8.8 cm, Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1163. Poussin, Nicholas, 1594-1665 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    Nicolas Poussin/Peintre. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 25.0 x 17.6 cm.
  - 1164. Poussin, Nicholas, 1594-1665 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    Nicolas Poussin. /J.B.Tilliard sculp. Bust in baroque oval looking right. Engraving. 11.7 x 8.4 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1165. Prance, Miles, ca 1680 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    Mr. Miles Prance./Discoverar of the Horrid Plott/and the Murtharers of Sr.E.B.God-free./R.White delin. et Sculps. Printed for Dorman Newman at the Kings Ames in ye Poultrey. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 24.3 x 15.9 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 24364/73821.
  - 1166. Prynne, William, 1600-1669 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    William Prynne./Natus 1600. Denatus 1889/From a drawing taken from the original Picture/ in the Prynne family in the possession of/Tho.s Lloyd Esq,r/London Published by S.Woodborn, l8ll./S.Woodford del. R.Dunkarton sc.t. Bust in oval looking left. Mezzotint. 15.6 x 10.7 cm.
  - 1167. Ptich, Johann Geong von, ca 1648 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    Joannes Georgius Baro del Puech in Walckersaich at Thami Decanus/Cathedralis Fnisingensis, Prepositus ad S.Petrum in Monte Madrano Sacrae/Caesarae Majestatis Consilianius et Reverendissimi at Serenissimi Pnincipis/Domini D.Alberti Sigismund Episcopi Frisingensis Utniusque Bavaniae/Ducis Comitis Palatini ad Rhanum Landgravij in Leuchtersberg/Consiliorum Praeces at ad Comitia Ratisbonensia Legatus./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petrus de Jo- de sculpsit. Accessit Pnivilegium Caesareum Gum pnivilegio Regum et Hollandiae ordinum etc. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Non est mortale quod opto.” Engraving. 31.6 x 21.0 cm. Singer No. 24549/74209. No. 123 from an unidentified edition of Hulle A. van, Celeberrimi ad pacificandun Christiani noininis orbern legatis.
  - 1168. Pulteney, William, 18th cent. (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    William Pulteney Esq./G.Kneller Bar.t. Pinx. 1717. J.Faber fecit. 1732. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. In right hand letter inscribed: "To the R.Hon.b. Will.m Pulteney./Secretary of War." Mezzotint. 35.1 x 25.2 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1169. Pupienus, Maximus Claudius, emperor of Rome, ?- 238 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    The Emperor Pupienus Maximus./P.Dujardin eng. Gebbie & Co. Unframad sculpture bust looking right. Photo-engraving. 36.5 x 26.7 cm. Torn from book.
  - 1170. Put, Hendrik van [Erylaeus Puteanus], 1574-1656 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
    Clanissimus Eycius Puteanus Histoniographus/Regius Professor Consiliarius Etc./Ant, van Dyck pinxit. Pet.de lode sculp. Gum pnivilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 23.0 x 17.1 cm. Singer No. 24589/74324. Dutuit No. 43.5a. Mauquoy-H. No. 36.VI. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1171. Putnam, Isreal, 1718-1790 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Major Genenal./Isreal Putnam. /Engraved by W.Humphrey from a sketch by Col. J. Trumbull P.A.A.F.A. Bust in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 22.7 x 13.9 cm.
  - 1172. Pya, Henry James, 1745-1813 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Henry James Pye Esq./Dnummond ad viv. pinx./J.Chapman sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving. 13.0 x 11.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1173. Pym, John, 1584-1643 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    John Pym Esq./In the Possession of Thomas Hales Esqr./J.Houbrakan sculps. Mist. Impensis J. & P.Knapton Londini, 1738. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly left, surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 36.5 x 23.3 cm. Singer No. 24607/74358. From: Birch T. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great ~ J.Knapton, London, 1743.
  - 1174. Quellin, Artus, 1625-1700 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Artus Quellinius Antvenpiensis/Curiae Anstalodamensium StatuarLus /Huber us Quelinus dalim at sculp. Half-portrait in oval looking left surrounded by oblong. Engraving. 31.2 x 22.3 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 24645/74449.
  - 1175. Quevedo de Villegas, Francisco Gomez, 1580-1645 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    [Quevedo]. Munillo pinx. H.Manasse sc./Imp. Wittman Paris. Bust in circle looking right. Etching. 16.7 x 15.3 cm.
  - 1176. Quinault, Philippe, 1635-1688 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Philippe Quinault./Auditeur des Comptes de l’Académ:Le f~aocorse /EoelincP scuipsit C P R Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 25.1 x 19.1 cm. Singer No. 24666/74499.
  - 1177. Rabalais, Francois, 1483-1553 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Rebelais./Gravé par Hopwood. Left profile in oblong. Stipple-engraving. 17.0 x 10.5 cm.
  - 1178. Racan Honore da Bueil, marquis de, 1589-1670 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Honorat de Bueil Marq./de Racan poeta, et de 1’Academie/françoisa né en Touraina i mourut/fort age. /E.Desrochers fecit. Bust in oval looking right. Five lines of eulogy ending: "Racan pouroit chanter au deffaut d’un Homére,” in lower center. Engraving. 14,4 x 10.3 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1179. Racine, Jean, 1639-1699 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Jean Racine./de l’Accadémie Prançoise./Edelinck Sculp. C.P.R. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 25.0 x 19.2 cm. Singer No. 24707/74638.
  - 1180. Raffaello, Sanzio, 1483-1520 (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
    Raphael, D'Urbin./Titian pin. De Larmessin sculp. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 18.3 x 13.8 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1181. Raffaello, Sanzio, 1483-1520 (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Raphael d'Urbino./J.Pass sculpt. Engraved for the Enciclopoedia Londinensis, 1826. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving. 18.0 x 13.2 cm.
  - 1182. Raffaelo, Sanqio, 1483-1520 (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Ille hic est Raphael, timuit quo sospite Vinci/Regum magma parens et non ante moni./ Questi è quel Rafael, cui vivo vinta/esser temeo natura, e monte estinta./Carol.Marattus inven.et delin. Bust in baroque oval looking right. Engraving. 28.5 x 18.0 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1183. Raigersperg, Nikolaus Georg von, 17th cent. (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Nicolaus Georgius de Raigespeng./Eques S.ra Gaes.ae M.tis Consilianius Impanialis Aulicus Eminentissimi Archiepisc. Pnincipis/Electoris Moguntini Cancallanius a Consilius/ Secretis et ad Tractatus Pads tJnivensalis/plenes cum postata Legatus./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. /Corn. Galle sculpslt. /accessit pnivilegium Caesareum/l649. /Gum privilegio Regum et/Hollandiae ordinum. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Cogita mon ante mortem.” Engraving. 30.6 x 19.6 cm. Singer No. 24796/74864. No. 60 from unidentified edition of Hulle A.van, Pacificatores orbis Chnistian
  - 1184. Rainsford, Sir Richard, 17th cent. (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Sir Richard Rainsford/Lord Chief Justice of the Kings Bench/Resigned 1678/From an original Picture half length size/London Published by S.Woodburn, :L8l5. R,Dunkarton sculpt. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 29.0 x 20.8 cm.
  - 1185. Ralegh [Raleigh], Sir Walter, 1552?-1618 (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    The true and lively portraiture/of the honorable and learned Knight/Sr.Walter Raleigh. Bust in oblong looking right. In partly missing lettered arch:”.. ,Smi Viri Dom.ni Gualthar Ralegh. Equ. Aur.etc.” Engraving. 12.2 x 7.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1186. Ralegh [Raleigh], Sir Walter, 1552?-1618 (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Vera Effigies Clanissimi yin Domini Gualthari Ralegh./ Bust in lettered oval looking slightly right. Under oblong: "The true and/lively portraiture/of the honorable/and learned Knight/Sr Walter/Raleigh.” "Amore at vintute.” over coat of arms. Engraving. 18.3 x 11.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1187. Ralegh [Raleigh], Sir Walter, 1552?-1618 (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Sir Walter Ralegh./Ravenet sculp. Bust in circle looking slightly left. Engraving. 10.0 x 9.8 cm.
  - 1188. Ralegh [Raleigh], Sir Walter, 1552?-1618 (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Sir Walter Raleigh./Ob.l618./From the original of Zucchero,in the Collection of/The most noble the Marquis of Bath./Engraved by H.Robinson./London. Published June 1.1829, by Harding & Lapard. Pall Mall East./Proof. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving, 24.0 x 17.9 cm.
  - 1189. Ramsbeck, Sebastian, 17th cent. (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    Sebastianus Ramspeck Basileensis/Practicae Philosophia in Academia./Heidelbergensi Prof.Ordinarius,Aetatis 44./Ano l659./Alaerdus Hinderich de Vos pin. Johan Schweizer sculsit. Bust in oval looking night.”Intuta quae indacora” in lower canter. Engraving. 17.3 x 12.7 cm.
  - 1190. Ranelagh Margaret Cecil, countess of, 1673-1727 (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
    The Countess of Ranelagh./G.Kneller Eques pinx, I.Smith fecit. Sold by I.Smith at the Lyon & Crown in Russel Street Covent Ga. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 33.5 x 24.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1191. Rapin, de Thoyras, Paul, 1661-1725 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    P.Rapin de Thoyras./G.Vertue del. et sculp. 1734. Bust looking right in oblong surrounded by composition of books. Engraving. Trimmed close to plate-mark. 32.6 x 22,0 cm. Singer No. 24880/75216. From: Birch, T., I ads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, London, 1756.
  - 1192. Rapin, de Thoyras, Paul, 1661-1725 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1193. Ravesteijn, Jan van, 1572-1653 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    Joannes Van Ravesteyn/Pictor Iconum Hagae Comatss Ant,van yck pinxit. Paul Pontius sculp. Gum pnivilegio. Half-portait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 23.5 x 16.0 cm. Singer No. 24966/75298. Dutuit No. 66.5e. Mauquoy-H. No. 60.VII.
  - 1194. Rawlinson, Sir Henry Creswicka, 1810-1895 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    H.Rawlinson./Pajnted by Henry Wyndham Phillips Espre A,D.1850, /Engraved by Samuel Cousin Esqre. R.A./London 9th May 1860. Published b~, lcssres Paul 8 Dominic Colnaghi & Co. 13 & 14 Pall Mall East. Seated half-figure facing viewer in oblong. Photo-engraving. 47.3 x 36.0 cm.
  - 1195. Ray [kajus], John, 1627-1705 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    Joannes Rajus./Societatis Regiae Socius./W.Eidet scuip. W,Falthorne plnxit. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 16.7 x 10.2 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 24970/75305.
  - 1196. Reede, Godart van, 1588-1648 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    Godard van Reede,/Graaf van Athlone enz./Veldmairschalk der VereenJgcle Nederlanden,/ A.Schounan del. naar't Onigineel by de Graavin van XXI lone (JHoubraken fec./IS,Tirion excud. Bust in oval looking left surrounded by oblong Engraving. 18.6 x 11.6 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1197. Reeda, Godart van, 1588-1648 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    Godardus de Reede./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit./Corn Galle tunior sculpsit 1648. Gum privilegio. Bust looking left. Engraving. 31.1 x 20.3 cm. Singer No. 25047/75497.
  - 1198. Reinhold, Karl Leonhardt, 1758-1823 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    K.L.Reinhold./geb. 26 Octbr. 1758 gest. 10 April. 1825./Copmann pinxit 1820, C.Ermar sculps. 1825. Unframed bust looking left. 17.9 x 11.0 cm.
  - 1199. Regnier, Mathunin, 1573-1613 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    Mathunin Régnier./Né en 1573. Mont en 1613./Ingouf Junior del. at sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 17.7 x 11.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1200. Reisen, Charles Christian, 1679-1725 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
    Charles Christian Reisen./J.Bretherlon f. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 17.3 x 13.1 cm.
  - 1201. Reland, Adniaen, 1676-1718 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Hadnianus Relandus, Aet. XXXVI./Enthea Piano Redimini tempera serto,/Formanique movie dignus imaginibus;/Hac meus impnessae Relandus imagine chartae/In toto cuivis orbe ni- dendus enit:/Nomen Erythrae is quod Eva per antra Lapillis/Non ingrata notent numina Nais des. Franciscus Hesselius Colasius pinxit. G.Broedelet axcudit. v.Gunst sculpsit. Bust in lettered oval looking right surrounded by oblong. Engraving. 35.2 x 23.2 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off. Singer No. 25244/75931.
  - 1202. Rembrant, Harmenszoon van Rijn, 1606-1669 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Portrait de Rembrandt./Rambrandt pinx. L.A.Claessens sculp. Bust in oval looking left. Etching. 17.8 x 15.0 cm.
  - 1203. Rembrandt, Harmenszoon van Rijn, 1606-1669 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Rembrandt./Rembrandt pinxit Masson del, at sculp./Chardon ainé et Axe imp. Bust in oval looking right. Photo-engraving.19.6 x 15.6 cm.
  - 1204. Randorp, Pieter, ?-1761 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Mr. Pieter Rendorp,/Heer van Marquette,/Burgenmeester en Raad/der Stad Amsterdam,/ Baljuw en Dykgraf van de Diener-meer enz./Frans van der Myn pinx. 1746. J.Houbraken fec. 1758, cum privilegio. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Engraving. 38.7 x 23.5 cm.
  - 1205. Reni, Guido, 1575-1642 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Guido Rhenus./Excelloit angramdes ordonances d'un esprit abondant: ses inventions sont asse/cognues par les estampes, qu'on voit de sa main faictes, en eau fort. le jour de sa nativite a été a Boloigne 1574: et mourut an l'an l642./Guid,Bhenus pinxit. I.Meyssens fecit at excudi. Bust in oblong looking slightly left. Engraving. 16.2 x 11.2 cm. From: Meyssens J. The true Effigies of the most eminent Painters that have flourished in Europe... Egg,raven, [Anvars], 1694.
  - 1206. Reni, Guido, 1575-1642 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Reni, Guido. Bust in baroque oval looking right. Engraving. 11.5 x 8.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1207. Renmell, James, 1742-1830 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    James Rennel./Scott del. Westenmayr sc. Right profile in oval. Etching. 13.7 x 8.3 cm.
  - 1208. Retaux de Villette, Louis Marc Antoine, 18th cent. (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Monsieur/Retaut de Villetta./A Paris chaz Basset rue St.Jacques pres las Mathurins. Bust in oval looking left in oblong. Ma z zo tmt. 26.5 x 17.9 cm. a. 1209. Rats, Claude Catherine de Clermont.
  - 1210. Reumont, Johannes von, ca 1648 (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
    Joannes de Reumont./Dominus in Naniru. Sacri Romani Imparij, nec non Regis/Hispaniarum Eques, sub arnis Caesarae Maiestatis/Generalis vigiliarum Praefectus. Colonellus legiomis/peditum at tempera tractatus pacis universalis Guberna/tor Civitatis Monaste- riensis./Accessit Privilegium Caesareum. Cum privilegio Regum at Hollandiae ordinum. Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petrus de lode sculpsit. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Ut bello constanter, sic at pace sincere." Engraving. 30.7 x 20.6 cm. No. 125 from Pacificatoresorbis ~hristiani, Rotterdam, 1697, Singer No. 25325/76155.
  - 1211. Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1723-1792 (Flat-box 10, Folder 5)
    Sir Joshua Reynolds Knt./Published Dec. 1.1783 by J.Fieding. No 23 Pater nester Row. Bust in circle looking right. Engraving. 11.2 x 17.5 cm, Torn from book.